

I believe in the capability of design to raise emotions and add value to everyday life. My designs are based on strong research and attention to details. My skills encompass the full project process and I'm able to adapt my knowledge to different fields of interest. My strengths are creativity, team working, thinking outside the box and problem-solving.

Turin (Italy)

+39 380 630 3328

design.jovita@gmail.com

jovitakau.com

EDUCATION

Oct 2018 - Oct 2020

Master of Science in Product Design

EQF level 7

Sapienza University of Rome, Rome(Italy)
110/110 with honors and dignity of pubblication

GPA 4.0/4.0

Nov 2014 - Oct 2017

Bachelor degree in Industrial Design

FOF level 6

ISIA Roma Design, Rome (Italy) 110/110 GPA 3.85/4.0

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Jan 2020 - Oct 2020

Honours Programme in Product Design

Sapienza University of Rome

Selected among the students of my faculty as one of the four most meritorious students for the Honours Programmes which provides further studies and additional training activities.

October 2020

First Prize for the project "Ventaglio"

Call for ideas: parametric furniture for smart working

Arken Group, Ferentino (Italy)

Designed a furniture system for smart working.

The product has been engineered and is currently on sale.

October 2016

First Prize for the project "GuidaMI"

AgID Gov Jam contest - Future Design: citizens at the centre

Agenzia per l'Italia Digitale, Rome (Italy)

Designed a service intended to simplify the communication between the public administration and the citizen through a personalized virtual experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Feb 2017 - Sept 2018

Design Intern

Officina 06 s.a.s. Rome (Italy)

Responsibilities

- · Designed and created personalized furnishing elements;
- Conducted design research and experimented with different materials;
- Developed the project through 2D / 3D software;
- · Cared for visual communication.

July 2019 - Nov 2020

Architectural Model Designer

Arch. Luca Garattini- Client Fendi S.r.I. Rome (Italy)

Responsibilities

- · Analysed and manipulated complex plans and elevations;
- Designed stylized scale models of interior design elements;
- · Realized architectural models.

page 1/2

PERSONAL SKILLS Digital Skills

3D MODELLING

- Rhinoceros
- Solidworks

RENDERING

- Rhinoceros V-ray
- Keyshot

CAD DESIGN

AutoCAD

VIDEO EDITING

Adobe After Effects

GRAPHIC DESIGN

- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe InDesign

WEB DESIGN

- HTML
- CSS
- UX & UI

Other Skills

PRACTICAL SKILLS

- Freehand Sketching
- Model Making
- Manual Skills and precision
- Laser Cut

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

- Team Work
- Decision.Making
- Problem solving

Languages

Italian (Mother tongue)

Lithuanian (Mother tongue)

English (level C1)

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages